[theme music playing]
[engine revving]
[Jerry] Really, what is the point
of a car like this?
It's small. It's impractical.
It's honestly just a ridiculous way
of moving people from place to place.
But in 1959,
it was cars like this Triumph TR3A,
in pearl white
with black top and interior,
that showed the world
how to have your childhood
and your adulthood at the same time.
It's got a four-cylinder engine,
105 horsepower,
wire wheels with knock-off hubs.
Adults have places to go, things to do.
Kids just want to play with something dumb
for no reason at all.
So, this is the perfect solution
to that eternal imperfection
of human life,
how to make sense and be completely silly,
simultaneously.
You could not have
a better context for this car.
-Which is why it's the perfect car...
-It's a beautiful car.
-...for my special guest this week...
-Bloking and crumpeting around...
...Mr. John Oliver,
the hilarious host
of HBO's Last Week Tonight,
and a perfectly logical,
absurd human being.
-That's your style, and I love it.
-Yeah.
[phone ringing]
-[John] Hello?
-[Jerry] Hello, John?
-Jerry, how are you doing?
-Couldn't be better.
[John]
Is that said with sarcasm or with truth?
-[Jerry] I abandoned the truth long ago.
-[John laughs]
-Well, we're gonna get along just fine.
-[Jerry] I'll be right there.
I'm Jerry Seinfeld,
and this is
Comedians In Cars Getting Coffee.
That's how a gentleman
greets another gentleman.
-What do you think?
-Well, I love it is what I think.
That's like the perfect British definition
of a sports car, isn't it?
-Yeah.
-Not even comfortable to get in.
This is your people, okay?
This is their idea.
You know, it does smell
like a Triumph, though.
[Jerry] We have got
a spectacularly British day today.
-[John] Perfect, right?
-It's perfect.
[John] It's a kind of low, gray sky
that sucks all joy from your heart.
[Jerry]
So, what do you think of it so far?
It's very cozy.
You can imagine yourself
on a date with, a what, a crumpet?
That what you're interested in
in England, crumpets?
You're blokes,
and you're in search of crumpets.
-Blokes and crumpets.
-Yeah. That's all I know about England.
Blokes and crumpets
feeling a lot of things,
-but not articulating anything.
-Right.
That was basically the history
-of British relationships there.
-Right.
"I love you, you love me, let's never
ever express that to each other.
Let's die frustrated and alone."
And that is the
ultimate British love story.
Good for them, they didn't act on it.
How long have you been here?
-Coming up on ten years.
-Ten.
-And you're still saying "fru-strated"?
-Yeah.
You haven't heard how we're talking?
-What do you say?
-Fru-strated.
No, that's... I can't do that.
You do hear the difference.
You just choose to ignore it.
In '59, this would be great.
We just got out of the Second World War,
a good percentage of us died,
and now the ones that are left
are driving around in these.
[Jerry] That's right.
That's exactly what happened.
The war ended.
-The English started making these cars...
-Yeah.
And everybody thought,
"Okay, we can go back to having fun now."
As much fun as we feel comfortable having.
Let's let the English
-show us how to have fun.
-That's true.
-Of any group you could pick.
-Yeah.
Did you go to college...
-Or university, I guess you'd call it?
-I did.
-Was that "fru-strating"?
-It was a little.
My wife was a combat medic.
She joined the army September 12th, 2001.
She was 19.
Wow. September 12th...
Yeah, straight after September the 11th.
Well, I know September 12th
is after September 11th.
How stupid do I look?
[John]
I think I was doing a gig in Pittsburgh.
I said it was a pretty rough gig,
and there were a lot of people
collapsing drunk outside,
and I said to her,
"It was like a war zone out there."
And she said, "Yeah, it wasn't.
I'm gonna give you a couple of minutes
to take that back,
because the Pittsburgh Improv,
I do not doubt, is a rough gig,
but it's not Fallujah rough."
I have been watching
so much of your stuff.
I really have to compliment you.
I'm not gonna use this
in the show, of course.
Tell me about the show
because I have to say, in all honesty,
I'm obsessed with it now,
and I don't even know what the hell it is.
Neither do I.
Is it just you talking? Is that it?
Pretty much.
[both laughing]
This is a cool area.
I think this is Williamsburg.
This used to be Orthodox Jews,
and now it's hipsters.
Two versions, really, of the same thing.
Let's all look alike.
[inaudible]
[John] Wow.
That is a judgmental silence
you just walked into.
I wouldn't describe this as a hush
because a hush is comfortable.
A hush has a softness to it.
-It is judgmental...
-That's a hard silence.
Welcome to my childhood.
Please do this gently,
do this smoothly, okay?
There's a table of women behind you,
four different colors of hair,
but be... be subtle, be smooth.
-I've got this. Don't worry about it.
-Yeah.
I was right.
We're dealing with the 'rents.
In England, ladies of a certain age,
when they want to
shake it up a little bit,
they'll go for purple.
Do men have anything like that?
I think, well, handsome men might.
I know there's no answers
for me in a haircut.
Well, you did make
an adjustment to your hair.
-I did, for the HBO show.
-Which I noted.
Before I became aware
of your comedy, I kept thinking,
-"What is this guy doing with the bangs?"
-That's true.
Because men with bangs disturb me.
-It's stand-up, there's different rules.
-It's different.
In stand-up, you want
a mongrel-y, cretinous, troll-like...
Where the limbs are moving...
-Out-from-under-a-bridge individual.
-Exactly.
-Suddenly into the daylight.
-Yeah. [laughs]
Guess there's a lot of inside stuff
about England
which just doesn't translate.
Like, it became clear that as soon as
this voice started criticizing America...
And listen, I understand that we have done
some terrible things through our history.
Nobody's really thinking
about that here. No.
Nobody cares about England.
So, let me disabuse you. You can relax.
We don't care where you're from.
-That is such a hurtful thing to say.
-You have a lovely, charming...
This little ding-a-ling... The door opens.
Ding-a-ling-a-ling.
-[groans]
-"Have you had a lovely day?"
We just think of the English as
a cute little... It's a curio shop to us.
-Ding-a-ling-a-ling.
-"Cup of tea, mister?"
-Yeah!
You don't even seem English.
You just seem like an unusual person
-who talks different...
-Uh-huh.
...but this guy's very funny.
The place that your voice comes from
does not feel English,
-even with the accent...
-Right.
And the glasses, the hair you got rid of.
-The whole thing?
-Yeah.
-And the...
-Yeah, the puppety walk...
I think that's why
your stuff is working so well.
-This did not work in Britain...
-It didn't?
...as well as it does here.
I used to go to
the Edinburgh Festival every year.
I had 100% walkout in Edinburgh.
Started with six people,
two leave, like, ten minutes in.
Twenty minutes in, another two leave.
I'm down to two, a couple.
The guy says, "I'm going to the bathroom."
So, now, I'm just left with the woman.
She's there with her bag,
and I see her hand reach down
to her bag about 25 minutes.
I said, "Are you leaving?"
She said, "Yeah."
Picks up the bag, walks out.
I remember the sound
of the door closing behind her.
-Now I'm in an empty room...
-Right.
...with a sound technician saying,
"Do you want to carry on?"
"No, it's over. The gig's over."
-Thanks so much.
-[Jerry laughs]
What about jokes about your wife?
How does that go down?
Does she understand that these
are meaningless thoughts and words...
My wife, it's taken...
16 years we've been married,
she finally understands
I don't mean any of this.
We will put any words together.
I was talking with Julia Louis-Dreyfus.
She said,
"You said you would never get married."
I said, "I still feel that way."
It doesn't even make sense.
So... But that's obviously funny.
So, do you pay for that comment?
No, she understands now.
-Now she knows.
-I don't know what I'm saying.
Right. That was a sequence of words
that you knew had a laugh
at the end of it.
-That's right. That's it.
-So, you said them. Yeah.
You just described my entire brain.
I did Letterman once,
and he was very interested in her.
-Your wife?
-Yeah, he was very interested in...
Like, what she'd done,
why she was with me.
I think he said during that, what he said,
"Does she think you're funny?"
And I said, honestly, "No."
She said, "Why would you say that?"
I said, "Because I'm not
your favorite comedian, right?
You like Gaffigan."
"Maybe just say I am, next time."
But then I was trying to explain,
"But that wouldn't be funny."
-You were a comedian when she met you.
-Sure, but the internal logic of comedy
is really hard for anyone
to understand from the outside.
And what is the internal logic of comedy?
That you'll do anything for a laugh,
like a sociopath.
That's right.
Today, I was just looking at
some of the stuff we have for this week.
So, if it's something
that we want to practice
to prove how easy it is to do,
like, we started this church to show
the extent to which
churches are tax-exempt.
-Yeah, yeah.
-That was funnier to me to then do it...
And then people did it,
just send in cash the next day...
-Like, just cash flying in.
-How much did you get?
-$70,000. It was huge.
-And who's got that money now?
-We donated it.
-All right.
-Would've been funnier to buy jet skis.
-Yes!
You should have bought a jet ski
and donated that.
Donate that to Doctors without Borders?
Yeah, two doctors on jet skis,
with the stethoscopes in the wind.
That's a great look.
-That's a fantastic look.
-Yeah.
-Have you ever jet skied?
-Yes, sir.
I can't picture you on a jet ski.
I like to explore things.
I don't expect to enjoy them,
but I am curious
what is working for other people.
Right.
Does your mind ever go
to a place you would like
to take the show,
or you think,
"I'd like to attempt this daily?"
I'm sure you get that question
all the time.
-Yeah, but that's not gonna happen.
-How do you know?
At the moment,
this is the platonic ideal.
I got it.
Now how long we'll be able to do that
at this pace and this level of intensity?
How long we can do that to our staff?
I don't know.
This is not... When I say sustainable,
months in the future...
You've heard environmental-type people
say that?
So, you're using the word,
but you don't really know
what it means or how to do it?
No. I just know that it's a word
that comforts people.
Yes.
-So, you'd sprinkle it in?
-Yeah.
-That's smart.
-Exactly, say sustainable
and watch people go,
"Good, we're gonna be okay, guys."
-Yeah, I don't know.
-You are a devastating human being.
HBO will let you do anything,
so you want to say, "Where is that line?
Let's see what 'anything' means,
shall we?"
So, I went to Russia to talk to Snowden,
and we were in trouble
the whole time there,
like, the Russians are mad we're there.
Can only imagine the Americans
are mad that we've gone.
-Right.
-And I get back home,
and it was really fun because,
you know, trouble is fun.
Yeah.
And my wife said, "I thought you were done
with this kind of stuff."
And I said, "Yeah, I don't think I'm done.
I don't think I'm done."
Why would she think you're done?
I don't want to start trouble
-between you.
-The rational brain...
"You're an adult, right? Don't need to...
What's the point?
-What are you trying to prove?"
-You have a child.
"We've got a child.
-That's right, we have a baby."
-Yes.
"Why are you going
to irritate the Russian government?"
-"Because it's funny."
-Wow.
I think it's like a kid.
Like, it's funny being in trouble
in a controlled situation
where you're not in that much trouble.
-Right.
-It's really funny.
You seem like
you wouldn't mind actual trouble.
I think... I wouldn't mind it
until I really encountered it.
Or if it was affecting someone else.
Sure. Sure, yeah.
That's what you're
supposed to say, right? Yeah.
-Definitely. No, definitely...
-In a sustainable way.
Oh, good.
-[Jerry] You had a good time?
-I had a great time.
-Me, too. Great time.
-Yeah.
Nothing that makes me happier than this.
-Nothing.
-Isn't it weird?
-I'm telling you, I'm at 10.
This is as comfortable as I get.
You've seen me in ways
-that my loved ones don't see me.
-Right.
-Because I'm just...
-You're just not there for them.
-You're not there for them.
-I'm as there as much as I can be.
-As much as you can be.
-Right.
God help us.
God Almighty, help us.
[inaudible]
This is a pinnacle
of English automotive culture right here.
I mean, they really came up
with something charming, irresistible.
That is just irresistible.
I like the massive English study
that was done about whether you get wetter
if you run to get out of the rain,
or if you walk,
so that you're not hit as forcibly
by the rain.
-Massive study.
-What was the conclusion to that study?
You get wetter walking.
No [bleep].
I'm glad that study was so massive.
That felt like that could have been
a study of two people.
-Okay, it's raining outside.
-You run.
Walk around the block,
run around the block.
-That's it.
-Guess what?
The guy that got back sooner was less wet.
-Yeah.
-"It's a study out of England?
Well, you already have my full,
undivided attention.
What are those hobbits
doing over there now?"
"Well, they wanted to decide
how you get the most wet."
"Of course they did. Please continue."
"One walked, one ran."
"Did he run, or was it a kind of
bizarre jog he threw down?"
Well, good.
That's what England does
now that they don't control
any of the world anymore.
My first key lime pie,
I ate off a tray outside a hotel room
-in a corridor in Houston.
-Right.
-It was delicious.
-Yeah.
There was two-thirds of it left,
and I ate all of it.
I was wondering whether they'd walk out
in the morning and say,
"Hold on a second,
what human animal
ate two-thirds of my key lime pie?"
-So, you stood there eating it?
-No, I took it.
-I took it into my room...
-Yeah.
...ate it, felt zero regret...
-...put the plate back outside...
-Right.
...and walked away confidently,
thinking nothing about that seemed
like a bad decision.
I would eat a roll off a room service tray
in a hallway of a hotel
well into my successful years.
-Of course!
-Who would think...
"Hey, let's poison this roll in case
there's a comic coming home at 3:00 a.m."
-That's not happening.
-"We can kill him."
What a security video that would be.
"NBC's Seinfeld
eating a roll off the floor
on his knees like a dog."
I'm not really interested in acting.
-I did this one sitcom.
-Yeah.
-I did this one dramatic scene.
-Right.
So, we're in a car just like this,
and we're really close,
and she starts crying in this scene.
And the only thing I'm thinking,
watching her, is,
"You're doing some amazing acting
right now."
-But she's getting nothing back from me.
-Nothing.
Just an audience member half-a-foot away
from her face, going, "That's good.
You're really crying, aren't you?
Those are actual tears on your face..."
If you ever catch a rerun of my TV series,
and you see me in any scene,
that is exactly what I'm thinking.
"I mean, wow, look at this guy acting."
"Look at this.
Look at the commitment on that face."
"Wait, they're really into this."
"Oh, it's my line now."
I was never ever there,
not unlike your marriage.
-[John] You gave them 100%.
-100%.
I'm here. I'm giving you everything I got.
I'm not leaving anything on the field.
You're getting my absolute best here.
[Jerry] This is really great.
I think we're gonna be friends.
[John laughing]
-[Jerry] Which was bigger? Trump?
-[John] Trump.
-That thing got out of hand.
-[Jerry] Yeah.
I think he has a big clown-y body, too,
that's kind of... It's squidgy.
It's something...
A kid would want to squeeze it, you know?
-That's right, to relieve stress.
-Yeah.
"I'm feeling tense... That's better.
That's better, I don't know why."
Yeah, he would make
a good little stress ball.
Yeah.
He would make a better stress ball
than a president, that's for sure.
And we're out.